PREETHI SUBRAMANIAM

8 years Experience in Software Development Phone: 9110456697. Email: preeticse35@gmail.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY										
Durafit	Co-founder & CTO	36 months	Dec 2018 – Present	Implemented entire process						
				and automation in zoho one						
Informatica Business	Senior Software	35 months	Jan 2015 to Nov 2018	Enhanced multiple Versions						
Solutions	Engineer			of MDM						
Huawei	Software Engineer	43 months	June 2011 to Dec 2014	Onsite- MDSP						
Technologies				Project,Nanjing,China						

- Strong Knowledge on Zoho Platform and its functionality.
- Sound knowledge and experience in Java programming language.
- Depth of understanding in Object Oriented Concepts and Data Structures.
- Good debugging and problem solving skills with excellent troubleshooting turnaround time.

PROJECT EXPERIENCE

DURAFIT – B2C Fitness Brand – 50 Crore Revenue

Dec 2018 – Till Date

- Managed Technology, Finance and Operation Team.
- Customized entire zoho one suite for internal process and systems for all the teams.
- Developed Durafit website using Zoho sites and WooCommerce.
- Created applications for inventory management, asset management and Hiring Management in Zoho Creator.
- Automated many jobs related to Operation, Finance and customer care team in Deluge and Java.
- Integrated third party application to zoho like eshipz, sms magic.

Informatica Business Solutions – Master Data Management

Jan 2015 - Nov 2018

- Involved in the design and development of IDD Enhancement requirements.
- Resolved performance based critical issues raised by the customer.
- Expertise in Master Data Management concepts and Methodologies.

	Huawei Technologies	Jun 2011 – Dec 2014		
Project 1: MDSP		Project 2: Promotion Platform		
	■ Complete ownership of SIS module in MDSP.	■ Implemented data migration from USDP to Media		
	■ Developed the key soap web services of SIS	promotion in java using struts and backed by oracle 11g.		
	■ Co-ordinated with Chinese team of 8 members.	■ Fixed major security issues involved in media promotion.		
	■ Awarded "Best New Talent" for valuable contribution,	■ Awarded "Best Quality Contribution" for developing		
	initiative and quality oriented attitude in the C02 project.	End-of-call whitelist feature of 3kloc in zero defects .		

TECHNICAL SKILLSETS				
Programming Languages	8 years' experience in JAVA programming language.			
Frameworks	8 months experience in spring framework. 10 months experience in struts framework.			
Front End Languages	nd Languages jsp, javascript, jquery, ajax, json, UXE(Huawei proprietary framework)			
Developer tools	PMD, findbugs, static checks, Hutaf(code coverage), source monitor, soap UI, burbsuite and webscarab(security related tools)			
Database	Oracle 11g, SQL server			

EDUCATION					
X	2005	Holy Angels, Salem	90%	Consistently ranked top 5 till X	
XII	2007	Bharatiya Vidya Bhavan, Erode	95.5%	Ranked 4th in a batch of 200 students	
BE(Computer Science)	2011	Government College of Tech, Coimbatore	8.8	Ranked 3rd in a department of 75 students	